e-patternscentral.com 2015-03-20

# Privacy Policy

[Annie's](http://annies-publishing.com/) and [subsidiaries](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_companies.html) operate 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

which adhere to industry standards in helping to assure our customers' privacy. All information, including transactions, customer accounts, and all correspondence, are handled with discretion and care. The policies below apply to all of the 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

Annie's owns and operates. By using our 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

, you agree to the collection and use of your information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Pledge. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not use our 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

.

**Anonymous Information Collected By Annie's**  
When you visit a Annie's 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

, Annie's will capture certain anonymous information from our visitors. This includes the Internet provider's name (e.g. AOL), paths taken through a given site, and "click stream" activity such as when you click on a banner advertisement. No information that could identify you as an individual is collected in this manner. 

Cookies are used as part of our statistical reporting and have no personal information tied to them. We use this technology to enhance your experience on our sites such as to help ensure that you are exposed to offers and products that are of interest to you. We do not capture email addresses or personal information through our use of cookies.

Information that is collected through the use of cookies and standard Web server log files may be used to enhance the content of our 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

to provide you with a better experience in the future, to respond to customer inquiries and suggestions, or to provide special offers to you.

Annie's may also share this non-identifiable information with third parties from time to time.

**Personal Information Collected By Annie's**  
From time to time while on a Annie's 

_[website](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

, we may ask you to provide personal information such as your name, address, telephone number, email address and credit card information. We may ask you to provide personal information when making a purchase, setting up an account, or joining one of our online programs. Annie's will use your personal information for the purpose for which it was provided and as otherwise set forth herein. We will not store your credit card information unless you instruct us to do so.  Annie's may combine your personal information with information collected by its 

_[subsidiaries](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_companies.html)_

or share it among its 

_[subsidiaries](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_companies.html)_

. Annie's may also supplement the information we collect with information from other sources to tailor our 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

, products and offerings to your needs.

When you make a purchase on our website or join a club via our website, we request you to provide financial information such as account or credit card numbers. We will use your financial information to bill you for products and services or otherwise process your transactions. By making a purchase on our website, you consent to our providing your financial information to our service providers and to such third parties as we determine is necessary to process your transactions. These third parties may include the credit card companies and banking institutions used to process the transaction.

**Your Email Address**  
If you have provided your email address to Annie's, from time to time you will receive emails from us with information and offers from Annie's and other companies that we feel would be of interest to you. With every commercial email, we will provide you with a link to opt-out from receiving future commercial email. You can also opt-out of receiving future email messages from us by emailing us at 

_[Privacy@Annies-Publishing.com](mailto:Privacy@Annies-Publishing.com)_

. Opt-out requests are usually handled as soon as the request is made. However, it may take up to ten days to process an opt-out request.

Because we want to ensure that those people who have opted out no longer receive commercial email from us, we may share our opt-out email addresses with our trusted third-party advertising partners who engage in email marketing to their customers on our behalf. As such, we may share the email addresses of persons who have opted out with these third parties for the sole purpose of scrubbing their email marketing lists with our opt-out list to remove the email addresses of those persons who have opted to no longer receive our commercial email announcements.

Please note that if you elect not to receive commercial email messages from us, we will continue to send you transactional related email, such as product recall information, or safety or security information, subscription information, membership details, account status, order confirmations, shipping confirmations, invoices and customer service related email.

Annie's will not share your email address with any third party except as expressly set forth in this policy or unless you have requested or consented to such disclosure.

**Offline Communications from Annie's**  
When you provide your name, address, and telephone number to Annie's, we may use this information to contact you with correspondence and promotional offers from Annie's. You always have the opportunity to choose to no longer receive these communications from us by emailing us at 

_[MailPreference@Annies-Publishing.com](mailto:MailPreference@Annies-Publishing.com)_

. 

**Offline Communications from other companies**  
From time to time we may also share your name, address and telephone number with certain select third parties whose products or services we think might be of interest to you. You always have the opportunity to request that your information no longer be shared with these third parties by emailing us at 

_[MailPreference@Annies-Publishing.com](mailto:MailPreference@Annies-Publishing.com)_

.

Please note that your removal from these communications will only apply to managing the sharing of your information in the future and not to information that may have already been shared with third parties, all as provided above in this Privacy Pledge. You will need to contact third parties that may contact you directly to delete your personal information that they may be using to contact you.

**Limited Disclosures of Your Personal Information**  
Your personal information may be passed on to a third party in the event of a merger, transfer of ownership assets or the bankruptcy of Annie's or any individual subsidiary.

We may also disclose specific personal information when we determine that such disclosure is necessary to comply with applicable law or to protect the interests or safety of Annie's or other visitors to the 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

.

We may share your personal information with certain independent contractors, vendors and suppliers with whom we contract to provide specific services and products related to our 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

or our business, such as hosting and maintaining our websites, chat rooms, providing credit card processing and fraud screening, operating activities on our behalf, authorizing credit card transactions, and developing applications for our 

_[website](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

and email services. Access to and use of your personal information by these contractors is limited to the information reasonably necessary in order for them to perform their limited function for us.

**Policy for individuals under 18**  
The Annie's 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

are not intended for persons under the age of 18. We will not knowingly collect any information from persons under 18. No information should be submitted or posted on 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

owned and operated by Annie's by children under 18.

**Security of Your Information**  
Annie's values your privacy and the security of your information. We utilize firewalls, secure access storage facilities and other industry standards to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

Our Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software is the industry standard and among the best software available today for secure online commerce transactions. It encrypts all of your personal information, including credit card number, name, and address, to protect the privacy of your information as it travels over the Internet. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we are committed to protecting your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us.

**Related sites and hyperlinks to other websites**  
Annie's 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

may include links to websites of other companies unaffiliated with Annie's. Please note that we are unable to review all such sites and take no responsibility for their content. Our privacy policy will no longer be in effect once you leave our 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites or for the privacy policies and practices of other third parties.

**Accessing Your Information**  
Annie's gives you the opportunity to remove or change personal information that you have provided to us or modify your preferences, by emailing us at 

_[Privacy@Annies-Publishing.com](mailto:Privacy@Annies-Publishing.com)_

.

If you prefer to contact Annie's by regular postal mail, please write to:

Annie's  
ATTN: Web Customer Service Inquiry  
23 Old Pecan Road  
Big Sandy, TX 76005

Please use the address provided on the individual 

_[websites](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

for general customer service questions. You may use this address if you'd prefer not to receive future Annie's mailings and/or mailings from other companies to which we make our mailing list available. Please be sure to specify the company name from which you received the mailing.

**Changes to this Pledge**  
Please note this Privacy Pledge may be changed from time to time. Any changes to this policy will be posted on this page. Please check this page regularly. By using a Annie's 

_[website](http://www.annies-publishing.com/pages/privacy_websites.html)_

, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Pledge.

**Questions**  
If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Pledge, please contact us at: Annie's,  
ATTN: Web Customer Service Inquiry, 23 Old Pecan Road, Big Sandy, TX 76005, (903) 636-4304 or 

_[Privacy@Annies-Publishing.com](mailto:Privacy@Annies-Publishing.com)_

.

**Effective date:** July 12, 2012
